<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>In-Between on zed tan</title>
    <link>https://www.zeddee.com/categories/in-between/</link>
    <description>Recent content in In-Between on zed tan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 15:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.zeddee.com/categories/in-between/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PSA — 1984 Available on the Internet Archive</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/1984-internet-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 15:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/1984-internet-archive/</guid>
      <description>(via Smashing Magazine)
The Internet Archive has put up the Austrian edition of 1984, both in pdf and in audio book form. The copyright for this edition of the book has apparently expired in, well, Austria. NB: obligatory copyright warning &amp;ndash; download and share at your own discretion. Here are the links to the files on the Internet Archive:
 PDF Audio book  George Orwell&amp;rsquo;s woke novel is an everyman&amp;rsquo;s introduction to one of the potential outcomes &amp;ndash; reductio ad absurdum &amp;ndash; of a &amp;ldquo;bad emperor&amp;rdquo; having come to power in a highly connected world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transit</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/transit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 04:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/transit/</guid>
      <description>I spent 2 years teaching my students about the paradox of transit. Consider the train. Or the bus, or the car. The bus I take on my morning commute is never the same bus, or if it is the same, I never notice because they all look the same. I am stationary on the bus — seated thigh to thigh with the next man or woman or child, or standing with an arm dangling from the plastic grip of one of those things that hang from the frame of the bus for some like us who do not hanker for the security of a standing pole but opt to swing free grounded by our own two feet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sandpit</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/sandpit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 02:21:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/sandpit/</guid>
      <description>M was standing toes deep at the school sandpit, white sneakers pushed up against small dunes of damp brown and clutching a small marble in his right hand. Marbles weren’t allowed in school, but he found one when he went to the sand pit to dust away his boredom. Found it squatting and watching the sand, as if reading the grains of tiny rock that, post-grade-school-recess, was damp and clumpy. He saw it half-buried and forgotten in a patch where someone had spilt a beverage of some sort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Climb the Triund in July and Other Stories</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/dont-climb-the-triund-in-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 03:18:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/dont-climb-the-triund-in-july/</guid>
      <description>Five of us spent 2 weeks in India missing the sun.
I began giving Hendric the look whenever he’d say we have to bring out the tripod to catch the sunrise/set, because: (1) the tripod was really stable, which meant that it was also heavy; (2) the sun was avoiding us.
That is not to say, of course, that we didn’t see the sun at all. The sun is all-present in the wide open skies of this part of South Asia where the clay-coloured buildings kept people (and their things) in a vaguely organised grid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Play THE BINDING OF ISAAC</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/why-i-play-the-binding-of-isaac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 03:18:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/why-i-play-the-binding-of-isaac/</guid>
      <description>Isaac is a game of navigation, one that takes you room from room to confront new monstrosities.  To date, I&amp;rsquo;ve clocked 439 hours on Edmund McMillen&amp;rsquo;s The Binding of Isaac: Afterbirth. This is the second of the Isaac games, which means that these 439 hours are on top of the 300ish hours I&amp;rsquo;ve spent on the first Binding of Issac. That&amp;rsquo;s an entire month of my life that I&amp;rsquo;ve spent on this game, and I&amp;rsquo;m not proud of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instagram&#39;s Photojournalism</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/instagram-photojournalists-artsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 20:25:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/instagram-photojournalists-artsy/</guid>
      <description>“I look at my Instagram feed and it’s a network; I’m seeing through the eyes of people around the world,” says the image-sharing app’s Teru Kuwayama. Following two decades as a noted photojournalist, covering war and humanitarian crises in Iraq, Afghanistan, Pakistan, and Kashmir, the TED Senior Fellow now works on the community team at Instagram, specifically with photojournalists and the wider photo community. “So many eyes and so many minds are coming online and being harnessed to this grid,” he says.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read Less</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/read-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 01:54:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/read-less/</guid>
      <description>I found out that the National Library extended the average user&amp;rsquo;s borrowing privileges, allowing them to borrow probably 60% more books than they usually could. Because I was sitting at 12 borrowed books at one time and desperately wanted to take home a well-worn issue of LUCKY PEACH (on ugly foods, if I remember correctly), I did my part as an active citizen and actually paid for a premium library membership &amp;ndash; which has led to todays situation where I stand at a balance of 33&amp;frasl;50 books borrowed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Lynch&#39;s BLUE VELVET: Beaumont v.s. Booth</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/david-lynchs-blue-velvet-beaumont-v-s-booth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 13:14:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/david-lynchs-blue-velvet-beaumont-v-s-booth/</guid>
      <description>Lynch&amp;rsquo;s BLUE VELVET is a film that I&amp;rsquo;ve come back to countless times, either out of the onset of a mood for strange, dark stories or out of sheer necessity (I&amp;rsquo;ve been taught this film/ have had to teach this film several times over the past few years). And each time, at each viewing, I always stop at the scene where Jeffrey Beaumont (MacLachlan) — such a child his character was — trapped in a car-ful of thugs telling Frank Booth (Hopper) to leave Dorothy Vallens (Rossellini) alone, to stop hitting her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Araki&#39;s Flowers</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/arakis-flowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 09:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/arakis-flowers/</guid>
      <description>Fig. 1 Araki&amp;rsquo;s wedding photograph (left); Photograph of Yoko, Araki&amp;rsquo;s wife (right).
(All pictures — unless stated otherwise — are photographs here are photographs of: Fuyumi, Namioka and Bernasconi, Francesca (eds.). Araki: Love and Death. Lugano: SilvanaEditoriale; Museo d&amp;rsquo;Arte: della Città di Lugano, 2004. I blame limited student resources and a then-pressing need to just get the assignment done)
(This essay was written sometime in the third quarter of 2012. I&amp;rsquo;ve revised it with what little I&amp;rsquo;ve learned over the years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Letter from my Future Self</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/a-letter-from-my-future-self/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 21:43:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/a-letter-from-my-future-self/</guid>
      <description>Today, I received a letter from my future self:
Dear Zed,
I&amp;rsquo;m still here.
Warmest.
 Other Letters from Future Selves
 Originally: ↬ Pohtecktoes
 Lyndsey
 Luo Er
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mis-Remembering THE LAST LIFE IN THE UNIVERSE</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/mis-remembering-the-last-life-in-the-universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 21:14:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/mis-remembering-the-last-life-in-the-universe/</guid>
      <description>The lizard wakes up and finds he&amp;rsquo;s the last lizard alive. His family and friends are all gone. Those he didn&amp;rsquo;t like, those who picked on him in school, are also gone. The lizard is all alone. He misses his family and friends. Even his enemies. It&amp;rsquo;s better being with your enemies than being alone. That&amp;rsquo;s what he thought. Staring at the sunset, he thinks. &amp;ldquo;What is the point in living&amp;hellip; If I don&amp;rsquo;t have anyone to talk to?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look and Look Again: Clang&#39;s Diptychs and Butterflies</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/look-and-look-again-clangs-diptychs-and-butterflies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 23:07:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/look-and-look-again-clangs-diptychs-and-butterflies/</guid>
      <description>When I say you are dreaming, so am I — Inneryennings
 Yenlin writes beautifully on John Clang&amp;rsquo;s photo-essay “Twilight Dreams of a Papilio Demoleus” and relates it to the motif of dream, specifically recalling the Chinese philosopher Zhuangzi&amp;rsquo;s dream about the butterfly. But perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s where it gets a bit fuzzy, like all dreams do when you begin to wake up.
Clang&amp;rsquo;s work is dreamy, in the sense that she describes, that one has to navigate the tension between &amp;ldquo;dream&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;reality&amp;rdquo; in most of his work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>