<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zed on zed tan</title>
    <link>https://www.zeddee.com/tags/zed/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zed on zed tan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 09:43:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.zeddee.com/tags/zed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>KILLSCREEN DAILY: What TIME got wrong about THE LAST OF US</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/killscreen-daily-what-time-got-wrong-about-the-last-of-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 09:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/killscreen-daily-what-time-got-wrong-about-the-last-of-us/</guid>
      <description>You’re not going to find deep-sea fish if you’re staring between your legs while knee deep in the neighbour’s wading pool. And you’re probably not going to get gripping photographs of dust-covered residents of a post-apocalyptic Boston if you’re sending your photographer into a videogame.
 That’s the sort of misunderstanding that typically comes out of traditional media outlets attempting to import their practices and modes of production into a medium that it does not particularly lend itself to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Araki&#39;s Flowers</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/arakis-flowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 09:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/arakis-flowers/</guid>
      <description>Fig. 1 Araki&amp;rsquo;s wedding photograph (left); Photograph of Yoko, Araki&amp;rsquo;s wife (right).
(All pictures — unless stated otherwise — are photographs here are photographs of: Fuyumi, Namioka and Bernasconi, Francesca (eds.). Araki: Love and Death. Lugano: SilvanaEditoriale; Museo d&amp;rsquo;Arte: della Città di Lugano, 2004. I blame limited student resources and a then-pressing need to just get the assignment done)
(This essay was written sometime in the third quarter of 2012. I&amp;rsquo;ve revised it with what little I&amp;rsquo;ve learned over the years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zed Reads 002</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/scratchpad/zed-reads-002/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 19:41:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/scratchpad/zed-reads-002/</guid>
      <description>This week: A quick peek at the ethics of Michale Haneke&amp;rsquo;s films, Žižek on the instability of nature, geeking out on a nifty hardware prototyping kit, and on Instagram and the inadequacy of current attitudes towards Intellectual Property.
Michael Haneke&amp;rsquo;s Cinema: The Ethic of the Image. &amp;ldquo;Introduction&amp;rdquo; | Catherine Wheatley. Berghahn Books, 2009 Wheatley&amp;rsquo;s book on Michael Haneke&amp;rsquo;s powerfully (emotionally) violent films has been on my to-read list for the longest time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zed Reads 001</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/scratchpad/zed-reads-001/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 20:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/scratchpad/zed-reads-001/</guid>
      <description>This is an attempt to catalogue and journal most of what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to read. It is an exercise in articulation, and (hopefully) quick writing and quick reading.
Tech Bitcoin — The Internet of Money | Startup Boy Great primer on what the Bitcoin is. It comes down to this: the Bitcoin is the digital equivalent of a physical coin. It&amp;rsquo;s mined by time and computing labour, and each coin is unique because built into every digital wallet is a database of sorts that tracks every single transaction, making sure that no bit coin can be spent twice over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mis-Remembering THE LAST LIFE IN THE UNIVERSE</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/mis-remembering-the-last-life-in-the-universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 21:14:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/mis-remembering-the-last-life-in-the-universe/</guid>
      <description>The lizard wakes up and finds he&amp;rsquo;s the last lizard alive. His family and friends are all gone. Those he didn&amp;rsquo;t like, those who picked on him in school, are also gone. The lizard is all alone. He misses his family and friends. Even his enemies. It&amp;rsquo;s better being with your enemies than being alone. That&amp;rsquo;s what he thought. Staring at the sunset, he thinks. &amp;ldquo;What is the point in living&amp;hellip; If I don&amp;rsquo;t have anyone to talk to?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>