<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zed on zed tan</title>
    <link>https://www.zeddee.com/tags/zed/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zed on zed tan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 23:25:35 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.zeddee.com/tags/zed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>We March Backwards Into the Future</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/we-march-backwards-into-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 23:25:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/we-march-backwards-into-the-future/</guid>
      <description>I am thinking of The Binding of Isaac, Y combinators, recursion, and Marshall MacLuhan.
I had a long conversation about death with a good friend today over economy rice (I remember someone telling me that eating economy rice alone is the saddest thing in the world). Our conversation skirted the rims of the contingency of death, about how death doesn&amp;rsquo;t discriminate, and how the only thing that insulates you from death is either divine influence, or not caring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSA — 1984 Available on the Internet Archive</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/1984-internet-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 15:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/1984-internet-archive/</guid>
      <description>(via Smashing Magazine)
The Internet Archive has put up the Austrian edition of 1984, both in pdf and in audio book form. The copyright for this edition of the book has apparently expired in, well, Austria. NB: obligatory copyright warning &amp;ndash; download and share at your own discretion. Here are the links to the files on the Internet Archive:
 PDF Audio book  George Orwell&amp;rsquo;s woke novel is an everyman&amp;rsquo;s introduction to one of the potential outcomes &amp;ndash; reductio ad absurdum &amp;ndash; of a &amp;ldquo;bad emperor&amp;rdquo; having come to power in a highly connected world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transit</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/transit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 04:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/transit/</guid>
      <description>I spent 2 years teaching my students about the paradox of transit. Consider the train. Or the bus, or the car. The bus I take on my morning commute is never the same bus, or if it is the same, I never notice because they all look the same. I am stationary on the bus — seated thigh to thigh with the next man or woman or child, or standing with an arm dangling from the plastic grip of one of those things that hang from the frame of the bus for some like us who do not hanker for the security of a standing pole but opt to swing free grounded by our own two feet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sandpit</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/sandpit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 02:21:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/sandpit/</guid>
      <description>M was standing toes deep at the school sandpit, white sneakers pushed up against small dunes of damp brown and clutching a small marble in his right hand. Marbles weren’t allowed in school, but he found one when he went to the sand pit to dust away his boredom. Found it squatting and watching the sand, as if reading the grains of tiny rock that, post-grade-school-recess, was damp and clumpy. He saw it half-buried and forgotten in a patch where someone had spilt a beverage of some sort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Climb the Triund in July and Other Stories</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/dont-climb-the-triund-in-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 03:18:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/dont-climb-the-triund-in-july/</guid>
      <description>Five of us spent 2 weeks in India missing the sun.
I began giving Hendric the look whenever he’d say we have to bring out the tripod to catch the sunrise/set, because: (1) the tripod was really stable, which meant that it was also heavy; (2) the sun was avoiding us.
That is not to say, of course, that we didn’t see the sun at all. The sun is all-present in the wide open skies of this part of South Asia where the clay-coloured buildings kept people (and their things) in a vaguely organised grid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Play THE BINDING OF ISAAC</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/why-i-play-the-binding-of-isaac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 03:18:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/why-i-play-the-binding-of-isaac/</guid>
      <description>To date, I&amp;rsquo;ve clocked 439 hours on Edmund McMillen&amp;rsquo;s The Binding of Isaac: Afterbirth.This is the second of the Isaac games, which means that these 439 hours are on top of the 300ish hours I&amp;rsquo;ve spent on the first Binding of Issac. That&amp;rsquo;s an entire month of my life that I&amp;rsquo;ve spent on this game, and I&amp;rsquo;m not proud of it. But this number stands for something (I hope) more than the hours I&amp;rsquo;ve spent perfecting maneuvering pixels with my keyboard, and I think it&amp;rsquo;s got to do with a sort of navigation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instagram&#39;s Photojournalism</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/instagram-photojournalists-artsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 20:25:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/instagram-photojournalists-artsy/</guid>
      <description>“I look at my Instagram feed and it’s a network; I’m seeing through the eyes of people around the world,” says the image-sharing app’s Teru Kuwayama. Following two decades as a noted photojournalist, covering war and humanitarian crises in Iraq, Afghanistan, Pakistan, and Kashmir, the TED Senior Fellow now works on the community team at Instagram, specifically with photojournalists and the wider photo community. “So many eyes and so many minds are coming online and being harnessed to this grid,” he says.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read Less</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/read-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 01:54:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/read-less/</guid>
      <description>I found out that the National Library extended the average user&amp;rsquo;s borrowing privileges, allowing them to borrow probably 60% more books than they usually could. Because I was sitting at 12 borrowed books at one time and desperately wanted to take home a well-worn issue of LUCKY PEACH (on ugly foods, if I remember correctly), I did my part as an active citizen and actually paid for a premium library membership &amp;ndash; which has led to todays situation where I stand at a balance of 33/50 books borrowed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eye of Computer Software and Crogan&#39;s Flight Simulator</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/crogans-flight-simulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 10:35:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/crogans-flight-simulator/</guid>
      <description>(*This short essay is a commentary on Patrick Crogan’s “Logistical Space” in _Gameplay Mode: War, Simulation, and Technoculture_1, relating it to how we think about computer aided drawing software.)
Before we attempt to make sense of software and its relation to our world, we have to acknowledge its history and how its underpinning technologies have shaped our perceptual world. Software that we interact with through the interface of the screen, mouse, and keyboard are not only means through which we consume and produce “digital” content — these screens and computer peripherals have also come a long way in structuring how we see and interact with the “real-world”3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pangdemonium&#39;s TRIBES a coming together of wit and heart.</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/pangdemoniums-tribes-a-coming-together-of-wit-and-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 15:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/pangdemoniums-tribes-a-coming-together-of-wit-and-heart/</guid>
      <description>©Pangdemonium
A family comedy-drama, Pangdemonium’s staging of Nina Raine’s play Tribes is a raucous event. It comes with the usual: squabbling family members, prejudiced father-figure, overt sibling rivalry, parents trying to get their children to “fuck off”. There’s a twist, though. The youngest and dearest son of the family, Billy (Thomas Pang, who just happens to share a surname with — but is unrelated to — both the artistic directors of the theatre company), is deaf from birth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KILLSCREEN DAILY: What TIME got wrong about THE LAST OF US</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/killscreen-daily-what-time-got-wrong-about-the-last-of-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 09:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/killscreen-daily-what-time-got-wrong-about-the-last-of-us/</guid>
      <description>You’re not going to find deep-sea fish if you’re staring between your legs while knee deep in the neighbour’s wading pool. And you’re probably not going to get gripping photographs of dust-covered residents of a post-apocalyptic Boston if you’re sending your photographer into a videogame.
 That’s the sort of misunderstanding that typically comes out of traditional media outlets attempting to import their practices and modes of production into a medium that it does not particularly lend itself to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Araki&#39;s Flowers</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/arakis-flowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 09:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/arakis-flowers/</guid>
      <description>Fig. 1 Araki&amp;rsquo;s wedding photograph (left); Photograph of Yoko, Araki&amp;rsquo;s wife (right).(All pictures — unless stated otherwise — are photographs here are photographs of: Fuyumi, Namioka and Bernasconi, Francesca (eds.). Araki: Love and Death. Lugano: SilvanaEditoriale; Museo d&amp;rsquo;Arte: della Città di Lugano, 2004. I blame limited student resources and a then-pressing need to just get the assignment done)
(This essay was written sometime in the third quarter of 2012. I&amp;rsquo;ve revised it with what little I&amp;rsquo;ve learned over the years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLB: Ban these books/films too.</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/nlb-ban-these-booksfilms-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 07:16:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/nlb-ban-these-booksfilms-too/</guid>
      <description>First done by Bertha Henson.
  On the Iliad, by Joshua Chiang.
  Ng Yi-Sheng on What You Can Do About it.
  Article on the banning of books by NLB on Today Online.
 (Updated 23:50, 10 Jul 2014: Clarified several of the entries, improved formatting.)
(Updated 00:00, 11 Jul 2014: Added link to Joshua Chiang&amp;rsquo;s open letter)
(Updated 00:015, 11 Jul 2014: Added link Ng Yi-Sheng&amp;rsquo;s appeal to writers and readers)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HER (2013): Human you, human me</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/her-2013-human-you-human-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 09:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/her-2013-human-you-human-me/</guid>
      <description>(Previously on Speak Simply) A friend of mine (who had the misfortune of being one of my brighter former students) asked me a month or so back about how and why one would frame “non-humans” in a story very obviously about humans. I thought it was a fairly simple question until I thought about it some more.
“Well of course it’s a simple question.” A toy or a robot in a story is more likely than not to take on anthropomorphic qualities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zed Reads 002</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/scratchpad/zed-reads-002/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 19:41:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/scratchpad/zed-reads-002/</guid>
      <description>This week: A quick peek at the ethics of Michale Haneke&amp;rsquo;s films, Žižek on the instability of nature, geeking out on a nifty hardware prototyping kit, and on Instagram and the inadequacy of current attitudes towards Intellectual Property.
Michael Haneke&amp;rsquo;s Cinema: The Ethic of the Image. &amp;ldquo;Introduction&amp;rdquo; | Catherine Wheatley. Berghahn Books, 2009 Wheatley&amp;rsquo;s book on Michael Haneke&amp;rsquo;s powerfully (emotionally) violent films has been on my to-read list for the longest time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zed Reads 001</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/scratchpad/zed-reads-001/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 20:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/scratchpad/zed-reads-001/</guid>
      <description>This is an attempt to catalogue and journal most of what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to read. It is an exercise in articulation, and (hopefully) quick writing and quick reading.
Tech Bitcoin — The Internet of Money | Startup Boy Great primer on what the Bitcoin is. It comes down to this: the Bitcoin is the digital equivalent of a physical coin. It&amp;rsquo;s mined by time and computing labour, and each coin is unique because built into every digital wallet is a database of sorts that tracks every single transaction, making sure that no bit coin can be spent twice over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Letter from my Future Self</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/a-letter-from-my-future-self/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 21:43:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/a-letter-from-my-future-self/</guid>
      <description>Today, I received a letter from my future self:
Dear Zed,
I&amp;rsquo;m still here.
Warmest.
 Other Letters from Future Selves
  Originally: ↬ Pohtecktoes
  Lyndsey
  Luo Er
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mis-Remembering THE LAST LIFE IN THE UNIVERSE</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/mis-remembering-the-last-life-in-the-universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 21:14:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/mis-remembering-the-last-life-in-the-universe/</guid>
      <description>The lizard wakes up and finds he&amp;rsquo;s the last lizard alive. His family and friends are all gone. Those he didn&amp;rsquo;t like, those who picked on him in school, are also gone. The lizard is all alone. He misses his family and friends. Even his enemies. It&amp;rsquo;s better being with your enemies than being alone. That&amp;rsquo;s what he thought. Staring at the sunset, he thinks. &amp;ldquo;What is the point in living&amp;hellip; If I don&amp;rsquo;t have anyone to talk to?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>