<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cinema on zed tan</title>
    <link>zeddee.com/tags/cinema/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cinema on zed tan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 17:50:27 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="zeddee.com/tags/cinema/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>San Junipero</title>
      <link>zeddee.com/posts/san-junipero/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 17:50:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>zeddee.com/posts/san-junipero/</guid>
      <description>San Junipero made me cry. It made me cry because it&amp;rsquo;s a story about a pair of lovers dealing with trauma, loss, and pain. Tears constitute an involuntary emotional response to presented stimuli — stimuli that usually exceeds a certain emotional threshold. We cry with joy, relief, pain, hurt, etc. Working with that assumption, we also know that crying can be caused, and by extension, manufactured. San Junipero, and the rest of Black Mirror, manufactures its audiences&amp;rsquo; response to the series to produce an illusion of edification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Westworld</title>
      <link>zeddee.com/posts/westworld-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 15:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>zeddee.com/posts/westworld-2016/</guid>
      <description>Over time, repetition becomes variation.
 Westworld (2016) managed to hold my attention for more than 6 episodes &amp;ndash; 6 (now 9) hours that I feel must result in a product, or at least a short introspective into what held my attention in the series where I drift off drastically in others.
Here are a few thoughts:
Total surveillance is mundane.  There are no moments where surveillance becomes a source of horror.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zed Reads 002</title>
      <link>zeddee.com/scratchpad/zed-reads-002/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 19:41:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>zeddee.com/scratchpad/zed-reads-002/</guid>
      <description>This week: A quick peek at the ethics of Michale Haneke&amp;rsquo;s films, Žižek on the instability of nature, geeking out on a nifty hardware prototyping kit, and on Instagram and the inadequacy of current attitudes towards Intellectual Property.
Michael Haneke&amp;rsquo;s Cinema: The Ethic of the Image. &amp;ldquo;Introduction&amp;rdquo; | Catherine Wheatley. Berghahn Books, 2009 Wheatley&amp;rsquo;s book on Michael Haneke&amp;rsquo;s powerfully (emotionally) violent films has been on my to-read list for the longest time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mis-Remembering THE LAST LIFE IN THE UNIVERSE</title>
      <link>zeddee.com/essays/mis-remembering-the-last-life-in-the-universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 21:14:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>zeddee.com/essays/mis-remembering-the-last-life-in-the-universe/</guid>
      <description>The lizard wakes up and finds he&amp;rsquo;s the last lizard alive. His family and friends are all gone. Those he didn&amp;rsquo;t like, those who picked on him in school, are also gone. The lizard is all alone. He misses his family and friends. Even his enemies. It&amp;rsquo;s better being with your enemies than being alone. That&amp;rsquo;s what he thought. Staring at the sunset, he thinks. &amp;ldquo;What is the point in living&amp;hellip; If I don&amp;rsquo;t have anyone to talk to?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>