<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on zed tan</title>
    <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on zed tan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 19:37:26 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.zeddee.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Learned From Being a First-time Dungeon Master</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/what-i-learned-from-being-a-first-time-dm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 19:37:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/what-i-learned-from-being-a-first-time-dm/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents Context 1. Focus on storytelling rather than mechanics 2. Keep it simple 3. Make combat change the game world 4. Work with your players tl;dr   Over the new year, a few close friends and I huddles over alcohol (much needed), cakies (cake-ish cookies; thanks✨), an iPad, paper, and dice to play our first Dungeons and Dragons game.
 I was volunteered as the first dungeon master (DM, for virtue-signalling).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We March Backwards Into the Future</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/we-march-backwards-into-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 23:25:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/we-march-backwards-into-the-future/</guid>
      <description>I am thinking of The Binding of Isaac, Y combinators, recursion, and Marshall MacLuhan.
I had a long conversation about death with a good friend today over economy rice (I remember someone telling me that eating economy rice alone is the saddest thing in the world). Our conversation skirted the rims of the contingency of death, about how death doesn&amp;rsquo;t discriminate, and how the only thing that insulates you from death is either divine influence, or not caring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018-01-01 Changelog</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/2018-01-01-changelog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 09:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/2018-01-01-changelog/</guid>
      <description>From 2017 and up
 Gained rudimentary proficiency in python, bash scripting, powershell scripting, SASS. Started learning a statically typed programming language. Had my first open-source pull request accepted Finished Agamben&amp;rsquo;s The Open Started on too many books. Built a content-driven website and was paid for it. Learned an authoring tool. Gained rudimentary proficiency in managing Docker containers. Learned many things about editorship and management. Bought a powerhouse PC. Played video games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Junipero</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/san-junipero/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 17:50:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/san-junipero/</guid>
      <description>San Junipero made me cry. It made me cry because it&amp;rsquo;s a story about a pair of lovers dealing with trauma, loss, and pain. Tears constitute an involuntary emotional response to presented stimuli — stimuli that usually exceeds a certain emotional threshold. We cry with joy, relief, pain, hurt, etc. Working with that assumption, we also know that crying can be caused, and by extension, manufactured. San Junipero, and the rest of Black Mirror, manufactures its audiences&amp;rsquo; response to the series to produce an illusion of edification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSA — 1984 Available on the Internet Archive</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/1984-internet-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 15:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/1984-internet-archive/</guid>
      <description>(via Smashing Magazine)
The Internet Archive has put up the Austrian edition of 1984, both in pdf and in audio book form. The copyright for this edition of the book has apparently expired in, well, Austria. NB: obligatory copyright warning &amp;ndash; download and share at your own discretion. Here are the links to the files on the Internet Archive:
 PDF Audio book  George Orwell&amp;rsquo;s woke novel is an everyman&amp;rsquo;s introduction to one of the potential outcomes &amp;ndash; reductio ad absurdum &amp;ndash; of a &amp;ldquo;bad emperor&amp;rdquo; having come to power in a highly connected world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Westworld</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/westworld-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 15:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/westworld-2016/</guid>
      <description>Over time, repetition becomes variation.
 Westworld (2016) managed to hold my attention for more than 6 episodes &amp;ndash; 6 (now 9) hours that I feel must result in a product, or at least a short introspective into what held my attention in the series where I drift off drastically in others.
Here are a few thoughts:
Total surveillance is mundane.  There are no moments where surveillance becomes a source of horror.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transit</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/transit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 04:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/transit/</guid>
      <description>I spent 2 years teaching my students about the paradox of transit. Consider the train. Or the bus, or the car. The bus I take on my morning commute is never the same bus, or if it is the same, I never notice because they all look the same. I am stationary on the bus — seated thigh to thigh with the next man or woman or child, or standing with an arm dangling from the plastic grip of one of those things that hang from the frame of the bus for some like us who do not hanker for the security of a standing pole but opt to swing free grounded by our own two feet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sandpit</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/sandpit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 02:21:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/sandpit/</guid>
      <description>M was standing toes deep at the school sandpit, white sneakers pushed up against small dunes of damp brown and clutching a small marble in his right hand. Marbles weren’t allowed in school, but he found one when he went to the sand pit to dust away his boredom. Found it squatting and watching the sand, as if reading the grains of tiny rock that, post-grade-school-recess, was damp and clumpy. He saw it half-buried and forgotten in a patch where someone had spilt a beverage of some sort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Climb the Triund in July and Other Stories</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/dont-climb-the-triund-in-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 03:18:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/dont-climb-the-triund-in-july/</guid>
      <description>Five of us spent 2 weeks in India missing the sun.
I began giving Hendric the look whenever he’d say we have to bring out the tripod to catch the sunrise/set, because: (1) the tripod was really stable, which meant that it was also heavy; (2) the sun was avoiding us.
That is not to say, of course, that we didn’t see the sun at all. The sun is all-present in the wide open skies of this part of South Asia where the clay-coloured buildings kept people (and their things) in a vaguely organised grid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Play THE BINDING OF ISAAC</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/why-i-play-the-binding-of-isaac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 03:18:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/why-i-play-the-binding-of-isaac/</guid>
      <description>Isaac is a game of navigation, one that takes you room from room to confront new monstrosities.  To date, I&amp;rsquo;ve clocked 439 hours on Edmund McMillen&amp;rsquo;s The Binding of Isaac: Afterbirth. This is the second of the Isaac games, which means that these 439 hours are on top of the 300ish hours I&amp;rsquo;ve spent on the first Binding of Issac. That&amp;rsquo;s an entire month of my life that I&amp;rsquo;ve spent on this game, and I&amp;rsquo;m not proud of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instagram&#39;s Photojournalism</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/instagram-photojournalists-artsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 20:25:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/instagram-photojournalists-artsy/</guid>
      <description>“I look at my Instagram feed and it’s a network; I’m seeing through the eyes of people around the world,” says the image-sharing app’s Teru Kuwayama. Following two decades as a noted photojournalist, covering war and humanitarian crises in Iraq, Afghanistan, Pakistan, and Kashmir, the TED Senior Fellow now works on the community team at Instagram, specifically with photojournalists and the wider photo community. “So many eyes and so many minds are coming online and being harnessed to this grid,” he says.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read Less</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/read-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 01:54:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/read-less/</guid>
      <description>I found out that the National Library extended the average user&amp;rsquo;s borrowing privileges, allowing them to borrow probably 60% more books than they usually could. Because I was sitting at 12 borrowed books at one time and desperately wanted to take home a well-worn issue of LUCKY PEACH (on ugly foods, if I remember correctly), I did my part as an active citizen and actually paid for a premium library membership &amp;ndash; which has led to todays situation where I stand at a balance of 33&amp;frasl;50 books borrowed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eye of Computer Software and Crogan&#39;s Flight Simulator</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/crogans-flight-simulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 10:35:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/crogans-flight-simulator/</guid>
      <description>(*This short essay is a commentary on Patrick Crogan’s “Logistical Space” in _Gameplay Mode: War, Simulation, and Technoculture_1, relating it to how we think about computer aided drawing software.)
 There is no war, then, without representation, no sophisticated weaponry without psychological mystification. Weapons are tools not just of destruction but also of perception — that is to say, stimulants that make themselves felt through chemical, neurological processes in the sense organs and the central nervous system, affecting human reactions and even the perceptual identification and differentiation of objects2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pangdemonium&#39;s TRIBES a coming together of wit and heart.</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/pangdemoniums-tribes-a-coming-together-of-wit-and-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 15:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/pangdemoniums-tribes-a-coming-together-of-wit-and-heart/</guid>
      <description>©Pangdemonium
A family comedy-drama, Pangdemonium’s staging of Nina Raine’s play Tribes is a raucous event. It comes with the usual: squabbling family members, prejudiced father-figure, overt sibling rivalry, parents trying to get their children to “fuck off”. There’s a twist, though. The youngest and dearest son of the family, Billy (Thomas Pang, who just happens to share a surname with — but is unrelated to — both the artistic directors of the theatre company), is deaf from birth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ian Bogost on The Design of Fun</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/ian-bogost-on-the-design-of-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 17:54:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/ian-bogost-on-the-design-of-fun/</guid>
      <description>I transcribed a YouTube video Ian Bogost&amp;rsquo;s WIRED talk on THE DESIGN OF GAMES and posted it on my Web Design and Technologies class blog. He touched on the material of play and the folly of the idea of &amp;ldquo;gamification,&amp;rdquo; both relevant in a world that&amp;rsquo;s been so intent on porting our physical world over to a virtual one without delving into what these practices really mean. A good watch if you&amp;rsquo;re into any sort of experience design and/or materialist philosophies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLB: Ban these books/films too.</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/nlb-ban-these-booksfilms-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 07:16:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/nlb-ban-these-booksfilms-too/</guid>
      <description>First done by Bertha Henson.
On the Iliad, by Joshua Chiang.
Ng Yi-Sheng on What You Can Do About it.
Article on the banning of books by NLB on Today Online.
 (Updated 23:50, 10 Jul 2014: Clarified several of the entries, improved formatting.)
(Updated 00:00, 11 Jul 2014: Added link to Joshua Chiang&amp;rsquo;s open letter)
(Updated 00:015, 11 Jul 2014: Added link Ng Yi-Sheng&amp;rsquo;s appeal to writers and readers)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HER (2013): Human you, human me</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/her-2013-human-you-human-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 09:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/her-2013-human-you-human-me/</guid>
      <description>(Previously on Speak Simply)
A friend of mine (who had the misfortune of being one of my brighter former students) asked me a month or so back about how and why one would frame “non-humans” in a story very obviously about humans. I thought it was a fairly simple question until I thought about it some more.
“Well of course it’s a simple question.” A toy or a robot in a story is more likely than not to take on anthropomorphic qualities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Letter from my Future Self</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/a-letter-from-my-future-self/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 21:43:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/a-letter-from-my-future-self/</guid>
      <description>Today, I received a letter from my future self:
Dear Zed,
I&amp;rsquo;m still here.
Warmest.
 Other Letters from Future Selves
 Originally: ↬ Pohtecktoes
 Lyndsey
 Luo Er
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Discourse and Opposing Same-Sex Marriages</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/public-discourse-and-opposing-same-sex-marriages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 19:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/public-discourse-and-opposing-same-sex-marriages/</guid>
      <description>Doug Mainwaring has written an article on why same-sex marriages shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a thing, stating that it&amp;rsquo;s a matter of semantics. Marriage, according to Mainwaring, is a term that is historically and culturally linked to heterosexual religious and legal unions. He says that we should leave the term &amp;ldquo;marriage&amp;rdquo; for the union of heterosexual couples, while homosexual couples should they want similar legal rights and recognition by the state/law should have &amp;ldquo;civil unions&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speak Simply: HER by Spike Jonze</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/speak-simply-her-by-spike-jonze/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 19:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/speak-simply-her-by-spike-jonze/</guid>
      <description>When I left the theatre, I heard the people next to me telling each other that they had &amp;ldquo;mixed feelings&amp;rdquo; about her. Granted, we&amp;rsquo;re probably not used to omniscient AI being portrayed in films as benevolent (and when they are, they&amp;rsquo;re given very human bodies 1), much less loving and capable of being loved.
But I won&amp;rsquo;t full-throttle into Wot-I-Think about _her_ here. That will come perhaps at some other time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look and Look Again: Clang&#39;s Diptychs and Butterflies</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/look-and-look-again-clangs-diptychs-and-butterflies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 23:07:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/look-and-look-again-clangs-diptychs-and-butterflies/</guid>
      <description>When I say you are dreaming, so am I — Inneryennings
 Yenlin writes beautifully on John Clang&amp;rsquo;s photo-essay “Twilight Dreams of a Papilio Demoleus” and relates it to the motif of dream, specifically recalling the Chinese philosopher Zhuangzi&amp;rsquo;s dream about the butterfly. But perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s where it gets a bit fuzzy, like all dreams do when you begin to wake up.
Clang&amp;rsquo;s work is dreamy, in the sense that she describes, that one has to navigate the tension between &amp;ldquo;dream&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;reality&amp;rdquo; in most of his work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Gamic and Cinematic Excess</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/on-gamic-and-cinematic-excess/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 22:46:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/on-gamic-and-cinematic-excess/</guid>
      <description>The Siege of Shanghai doesn’t have a plot for its unchecked materiality to overthrow. But it does have a structure. The five flags are laid out so as to create zones of control, chokepoints at which armor can be obstructed or destroyed, sight lines, multiple access points for infantry, etc. Returning players grok these elements almost instantly, routing themselves through the less-exposed paths and finding vantage points on well-traveled areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In My Hands: A Glimpse</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/71/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 21:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/71/</guid>
      <description>We often try to touch something to find out if it is really there. Material presence of an object is determined by its material tangibility, or in other words, &amp;ldquo;I can touch it, therefore it is there.
 Film theorists often looked to the &amp;ldquo;plastic&amp;rdquo; materiality of film, photographic and cinematic alike, as proof of their &amp;ldquo;here-ness&amp;rdquo;. This became of exceptional importance when it came to discussing the &amp;ldquo;realism&amp;rdquo; of the filmic image: that the plastic materiality of the filmic image would anchor its validity as index to its referent.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>