<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cinema Studies on zed tan</title>
    <link>https://www.zeddee.com/tags/cinema-studies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cinema Studies on zed tan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 09:28:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.zeddee.com/tags/cinema-studies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>HER (2013): Human you, human me</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/her-2013-human-you-human-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 09:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/her-2013-human-you-human-me/</guid>
      <description>(Previously on Speak Simply)
A friend of mine (who had the misfortune of being one of my brighter former students) asked me a month or so back about how and why one would frame “non-humans” in a story very obviously about humans. I thought it was a fairly simple question until I thought about it some more.
“Well of course it’s a simple question.” A toy or a robot in a story is more likely than not to take on anthropomorphic qualities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zed Reads 002</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/scratchpad/zed-reads-002/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 19:41:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/scratchpad/zed-reads-002/</guid>
      <description>This week: A quick peek at the ethics of Michale Haneke&amp;rsquo;s films, Žižek on the instability of nature, geeking out on a nifty hardware prototyping kit, and on Instagram and the inadequacy of current attitudes towards Intellectual Property.
Michael Haneke&amp;rsquo;s Cinema: The Ethic of the Image. &amp;ldquo;Introduction&amp;rdquo; | Catherine Wheatley. Berghahn Books, 2009 Wheatley&amp;rsquo;s book on Michael Haneke&amp;rsquo;s powerfully (emotionally) violent films has been on my to-read list for the longest time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look and Look Again: Clang&#39;s Diptychs and Butterflies</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/look-and-look-again-clangs-diptychs-and-butterflies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 23:07:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/look-and-look-again-clangs-diptychs-and-butterflies/</guid>
      <description>When I say you are dreaming, so am I — Inneryennings
 Yenlin writes beautifully on John Clang&amp;rsquo;s photo-essay “Twilight Dreams of a Papilio Demoleus” and relates it to the motif of dream, specifically recalling the Chinese philosopher Zhuangzi&amp;rsquo;s dream about the butterfly. But perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s where it gets a bit fuzzy, like all dreams do when you begin to wake up.
Clang&amp;rsquo;s work is dreamy, in the sense that she describes, that one has to navigate the tension between &amp;ldquo;dream&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;reality&amp;rdquo; in most of his work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Gamic and Cinematic Excess</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/on-gamic-and-cinematic-excess/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 22:46:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/on-gamic-and-cinematic-excess/</guid>
      <description>The Siege of Shanghai doesn’t have a plot for its unchecked materiality to overthrow. But it does have a structure. The five flags are laid out so as to create zones of control, chokepoints at which armor can be obstructed or destroyed, sight lines, multiple access points for infantry, etc. Returning players grok these elements almost instantly, routing themselves through the less-exposed paths and finding vantage points on well-traveled areas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>