<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Genre Theory on zed tan</title>
    <link>https://www.zeddee.com/tags/genre-theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Genre Theory on zed tan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 20:14:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.zeddee.com/tags/genre-theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Zed Reads 001</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/scratchpad/zed-reads-001/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 20:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/scratchpad/zed-reads-001/</guid>
      <description>This is an attempt to catalogue and journal most of what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to read. It is an exercise in articulation, and (hopefully) quick writing and quick reading.
Tech Bitcoin — The Internet of Money | Startup Boy Great primer on what the Bitcoin is. It comes down to this: the Bitcoin is the digital equivalent of a physical coin. It&amp;rsquo;s mined by time and computing labour, and each coin is unique because built into every digital wallet is a database of sorts that tracks every single transaction, making sure that no bit coin can be spent twice over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Uneasy Heroism of Taxi Driver</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/the-uneasy-heroism-of-taxi-driver/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 21:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/the-uneasy-heroism-of-taxi-driver/</guid>
      <description>Scorsese&amp;rsquo;s Taxi Driver (1976) is a film that escapes conventional genre definition, something that a quick survey of online movie reviews reveals: Scheib reads it as a psychological thriller — albeit one turned upon its head because the film&amp;rsquo;s protagonist is also the source of psychological fear1; Dread Central claims it as one of their own, citing the penultimate scene of the film as characteristic of a &amp;ldquo;slasher&amp;rdquo; film2, while choosing to ignore the markedly Noir aesthetic of the rest of the film.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>