<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Op-Ed on zed tan</title>
    <link>https://www.zeddee.com/categories/op-ed/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Op-Ed on zed tan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 09:43:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.zeddee.com/categories/op-ed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>KILLSCREEN DAILY: What TIME got wrong about THE LAST OF US</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/killscreen-daily-what-time-got-wrong-about-the-last-of-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 09:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/killscreen-daily-what-time-got-wrong-about-the-last-of-us/</guid>
      <description>You’re not going to find deep-sea fish if you’re staring between your legs while knee deep in the neighbour’s wading pool. And you’re probably not going to get gripping photographs of dust-covered residents of a post-apocalyptic Boston if you’re sending your photographer into a videogame.
 That’s the sort of misunderstanding that typically comes out of traditional media outlets attempting to import their practices and modes of production into a medium that it does not particularly lend itself to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Lynch&#39;s BLUE VELVET: Beaumont v.s. Booth</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/david-lynchs-blue-velvet-beaumont-v-s-booth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 13:14:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/david-lynchs-blue-velvet-beaumont-v-s-booth/</guid>
      <description>Lynch&amp;rsquo;s BLUE VELVET is a film that I&amp;rsquo;ve come back to countless times, either out of the onset of a mood for strange, dark stories or out of sheer necessity (I&amp;rsquo;ve been taught this film/ have had to teach this film several times over the past few years). And each time, at each viewing, I always stop at the scene where Jeffrey Beaumont (MacLachlan) — such a child his character was — trapped in a car-ful of thugs telling Frank Booth (Hopper) to leave Dorothy Vallens (Rossellini) alone, to stop hitting her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLB: Ban these books/films too.</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/nlb-ban-these-booksfilms-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 07:16:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/nlb-ban-these-booksfilms-too/</guid>
      <description>First done by Bertha Henson.
  On the Iliad, by Joshua Chiang.
  Ng Yi-Sheng on What You Can Do About it.
  Article on the banning of books by NLB on Today Online.
 (Updated 23:50, 10 Jul 2014: Clarified several of the entries, improved formatting.)
(Updated 00:00, 11 Jul 2014: Added link to Joshua Chiang&amp;rsquo;s open letter)
(Updated 00:015, 11 Jul 2014: Added link Ng Yi-Sheng&amp;rsquo;s appeal to writers and readers)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black and White are Only Two Colours: On Mark Laita&#39;s CREATED EQUAL</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/black-and-white-are-only-two-colours-on-mark-laitas-created-equal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 14:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/black-and-white-are-only-two-colours-on-mark-laitas-created-equal/</guid>
      <description>Fig.1: &amp;ldquo;Polygamists/Pimp&amp;rdquo; (Laita)1Mark Laita&amp;rsquo;s CREATED EQUAL2 is a curious piece. In each photographic frame, one or more subjects gaze back at the camera with eyes outlined by the glow of the single LED panel placed just slightly to the left of the camera. The “Pimp’s” sunglasses (Fig.1) catch its iridescent glow, and hides everything else behind it.
I have not read the book, so I don’t pretend to know what it’s entirely about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HER (2013): Human you, human me</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/her-2013-human-you-human-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 09:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/her-2013-human-you-human-me/</guid>
      <description>(Previously on Speak Simply) A friend of mine (who had the misfortune of being one of my brighter former students) asked me a month or so back about how and why one would frame “non-humans” in a story very obviously about humans. I thought it was a fairly simple question until I thought about it some more.
“Well of course it’s a simple question.” A toy or a robot in a story is more likely than not to take on anthropomorphic qualities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zed Reads 002</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/scratchpad/zed-reads-002/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 19:41:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/scratchpad/zed-reads-002/</guid>
      <description>This week: A quick peek at the ethics of Michale Haneke&amp;rsquo;s films, Žižek on the instability of nature, geeking out on a nifty hardware prototyping kit, and on Instagram and the inadequacy of current attitudes towards Intellectual Property.
Michael Haneke&amp;rsquo;s Cinema: The Ethic of the Image. &amp;ldquo;Introduction&amp;rdquo; | Catherine Wheatley. Berghahn Books, 2009 Wheatley&amp;rsquo;s book on Michael Haneke&amp;rsquo;s powerfully (emotionally) violent films has been on my to-read list for the longest time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zed Reads 001</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/scratchpad/zed-reads-001/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 20:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/scratchpad/zed-reads-001/</guid>
      <description>This is an attempt to catalogue and journal most of what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to read. It is an exercise in articulation, and (hopefully) quick writing and quick reading.
Tech Bitcoin — The Internet of Money | Startup Boy Great primer on what the Bitcoin is. It comes down to this: the Bitcoin is the digital equivalent of a physical coin. It&amp;rsquo;s mined by time and computing labour, and each coin is unique because built into every digital wallet is a database of sorts that tracks every single transaction, making sure that no bit coin can be spent twice over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mis-Remembering THE LAST LIFE IN THE UNIVERSE</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/mis-remembering-the-last-life-in-the-universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 21:14:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/essays/mis-remembering-the-last-life-in-the-universe/</guid>
      <description>The lizard wakes up and finds he&amp;rsquo;s the last lizard alive. His family and friends are all gone. Those he didn&amp;rsquo;t like, those who picked on him in school, are also gone. The lizard is all alone. He misses his family and friends. Even his enemies. It&amp;rsquo;s better being with your enemies than being alone. That&amp;rsquo;s what he thought. Staring at the sunset, he thinks. &amp;ldquo;What is the point in living&amp;hellip; If I don&amp;rsquo;t have anyone to talk to?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speak Simply: HER by Spike Jonze</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/speak-simply-her-by-spike-jonze/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 19:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/speak-simply-her-by-spike-jonze/</guid>
      <description>_ _
When I left the theatre, I heard the people next to me telling each other that they had &amp;ldquo;mixed feelings&amp;rdquo; about her. Granted, we&amp;rsquo;re probably not used to omniscient AI being portrayed in films as benevolent (and when they are, they&amp;rsquo;re given very human bodies 1), much less loving and capable of being loved.
But I won&amp;rsquo;t full-throttle into Wot-I-Think about her here. That will come perhaps at some other time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look and Look Again: Clang&#39;s Diptychs and Butterflies</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/look-and-look-again-clangs-diptychs-and-butterflies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 23:07:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/look-and-look-again-clangs-diptychs-and-butterflies/</guid>
      <description>When I say you are dreaming, so am I — Inneryennings
 Yenlin writes beautifully on John Clang&amp;rsquo;s photo-essay “Twilight Dreams of a Papilio Demoleus” and relates it to the motif of dream, specifically recalling the Chinese philosopher Zhuangzi&amp;rsquo;s dream about the butterfly. But perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s where it gets a bit fuzzy, like all dreams do when you begin to wake up.
Clang&amp;rsquo;s work is dreamy, in the sense that she describes, that one has to navigate the tension between &amp;ldquo;dream&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;reality&amp;rdquo; in most of his work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Gamic and Cinematic Excess</title>
      <link>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/on-gamic-and-cinematic-excess/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 22:46:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zeddee.com/posts/on-gamic-and-cinematic-excess/</guid>
      <description>The Siege of Shanghai doesn’t have a plot for its unchecked materiality to overthrow. But it does have a structure. The five flags are laid out so as to create zones of control, chokepoints at which armor can be obstructed or destroyed, sight lines, multiple access points for infantry, etc. Returning players grok these elements almost instantly, routing themselves through the less-exposed paths and finding vantage points on well-traveled areas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>