<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scratchpads on zed tan</title>
    <link>/scratchpad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scratchpads on zed tan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 18:22:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/scratchpad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Levinas -- &#34;Suffering and Death&#34;</title>
      <link>/scratchpad/levinas-suffering-and-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 18:22:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scratchpad/levinas-suffering-and-death/</guid>
      <description>“Suffering and Death”1 — Levinas Emmanuel Levinas, “Suffering and Death,” Time &amp;amp; the Other, trans. Richard A. Cohen (Pittsburg, Pennsylvania: Duquesne UP, 1987), p. 68–71.
(Text below is excerpted from &amp;ldquo;Suffering and Death&amp;rdquo;)
In pain, sorrow, and suffering, we once again find, in a state of purity, the finality that constitutes the tragedy of {page break; 68} solitude. The ecstasies of enjoyment does not succeed in surmounting this finality. Two points must be emphasized: I am going to pursue the analysis of solitude in the pain of need and work, not in the anxiety of nothingness; and I am going to lay stress on the pain lightly called physical, for in it engagement in existence without any equivocation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Strasser — “Rags, Bones, and Plastic Bags”</title>
      <link>/scratchpad/strasser-rags-bones-plastic-bags/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 17:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scratchpad/strasser-rags-bones-plastic-bags/</guid>
      <description>Strasser, Susan, “Rags, Bones, and Plastic Bags: Obsolescence, Trash, and American Consumer Culture,” in Babette B. Tischleder and Sarah Wasserman (ed.s), Cultures of Obsolescence: History, Materiality, and the Digital Age (NY: Palgrave MacMillan, 2015), pp. 41–60.
NB: Strasser’s research mostly reveals only what was happening in the US.
How the the growth of consumer culture can be traced through the history of trash:
“Stewardship of Objects and Materials” (42–45) Strasser charts the history of 19th-century household manuals — containing advice for housekeepers on maintenance of household objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Bonfires</title>
      <link>/scratchpad/on-bonfires/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 19:43:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scratchpad/on-bonfires/</guid>
      <description>Bonfires 
&amp;quot;Figures 047 The Lord Appears to Moses in a Burning Bush&amp;quot; by illustrators of the 1728 Figures de la Bible, Gerard Hoet (1648–1733) and others, published by P. de Hondt in The Hague in 1728 - http://www.mythfolklore.net/lahaye/047/LaHaye1728Figures047ExodIII2-10BurningBush.jpg. Licensed under Public Domain via Wikimedia Commons

&amp;quot;Foster Bible Pictures 0060-1 Moses Sees a Fire Burning in a Bush&amp;quot; by Illustrators of the 1897 Bible Pictures and What They Teach Us by Charles Foster - http://associate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Notes on Consumerism</title>
      <link>/scratchpad/notes-on-consumerism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 19:29:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scratchpad/notes-on-consumerism/</guid>
      <description>Consumerism 
The Consumption Reader Unless otherwise specified, all quotes are from the following text:
Clarke, David B., Doel, Marcus A., Housiaux, Kate M.L. (ed.) The Consumption Reader (London &amp;amp; NY: Routledge, 2003).
“General Introduction” p.1
 Introducing ‘consumption’ is a daunting task, not simply because there has been an explosion of writing and research on the topic over recent decades, but also because most people already feel they understand the term well enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on George Perec&#39;s Species of Spaces and Other Pieces</title>
      <link>/scratchpad/georges-perec-species-of-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 15:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scratchpad/georges-perec-species-of-spaces/</guid>
      <description>Perec, Georges, Species of Spaces and Other Pieces (Penguin Classics, 2008) Perec&amp;rsquo;s text here reads as a beautiful taxonomy of spaces, but markedly avoids writing this taxonomy as a list of definitions. Instead, he navigates and dances around the spaces that we take for granted, the spaces that remain invisible to us until someone like himself comes along and — with his two writerly hands — cups its and holds it up gently to our faces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zed Reads 002</title>
      <link>/scratchpad/zed-reads-002/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 19:41:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scratchpad/zed-reads-002/</guid>
      <description>This week: A quick peek at the ethics of Michale Haneke&amp;rsquo;s films, Žižek on the instability of nature, geeking out on a nifty hardware prototyping kit, and on Instagram and the inadequacy of current attitudes towards Intellectual Property.
Michael Haneke&amp;rsquo;s Cinema: The Ethic of the Image. &amp;ldquo;Introduction&amp;rdquo; | Catherine Wheatley. Berghahn Books, 2009 Wheatley&amp;rsquo;s book on Michael Haneke&amp;rsquo;s powerfully (emotionally) violent films has been on my to-read list for the longest time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zed Reads 001</title>
      <link>/scratchpad/zed-reads-001/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 20:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scratchpad/zed-reads-001/</guid>
      <description>This is an attempt to catalogue and journal most of what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to read. It is an exercise in articulation, and (hopefully) quick writing and quick reading.
Tech Bitcoin — The Internet of Money | Startup Boy Great primer on what the Bitcoin is. It comes down to this: the Bitcoin is the digital equivalent of a physical coin. It&amp;rsquo;s mined by time and computing labour, and each coin is unique because built into every digital wallet is a database of sorts that tracks every single transaction, making sure that no bit coin can be spent twice over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aporia of the Touchscreen</title>
      <link>/scratchpad/kaerlein-aporias-touchscreen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scratchpad/kaerlein-aporias-touchscreen/</guid>
      <description>Aporia of Touchscreen Kaerlein, Timo, “Aporias of the touchscreen: On the promises and perils of a ubiquitous technology,” NECSUS: European Journal of Media Studies, published on 22 Nov 2012, available: &amp;lt;[www.necsus-ejms.org/aporias-of-the-touchscreen-on-the-promises-and-perils-of-a-ubiquitous-technology]&amp;gt;
On Aporia: &amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;More refined as a term, it attempts to outline a state of emergency, a system pressure, an ‘urgence’ in the Foucaultian sense,[6] that can serve to explain the success of the touchscreen technology in being a reaction to an exigent problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>